Mss.B.G784
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Card to J[ohn] E. Gray, undated; 3-1/2x4-3/4; Gervais, Paul, 1816-1879
    A.D.S. 1p. In French. Presents his compliments.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 6x4-1/4; Gervais, Paul, 1816-1879
    A.L.S. 1p., end. In French. Asks if items from M. Stahl, of the French museum, have been received by the British museum.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 7x4-1/2; Gilles, James
    Monday. A.L.S. 2p. Will call for the stamp book.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, undated; 7x4-1/4; Godwin, George, 1815-1888
    Brompton, A.L.S. 2p. Thanks him for the remembrance. February 23
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Gordon, George Hamilton, Earl of Aberdeen, 1784-1860.
    A.L.S. 2p. Returns pamphlets.
    August 12
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, undated; 7x4-1/2; Gordon, George Hamilton, Earl of Aberdeen, 1784-1860.
    A.L.S. 3p. Thanks for publication. News of friends.
    October 30
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 7x4-1/2; Gould, John, 1804-1881
    A.L.S. 1p. Encloses cards. Will be happy to see them when they call.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 7x4-1/2; Graham, Thomas, 1805-1869
    March 22
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Grainger, Richard Dugard, 1801-1865
    A.L.S. 2p. Has already promised his vote.
  - Photograph, two clipped signatures, undated
    Gray, John Edward
  - Letter to Mrs Paget, undated; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to Mr. & Mrs. Gray, undated; 3-3/4x3-1/2; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888.
    L. in 3rd. P. 1p. Accepts invitation.
    February 12
  - Letter to "My dear Dixon", undated; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 4x3-1/2; Greenough, George Bellas, 1778-1855
    A.L.S. 1p. Sends a list of societies.
  - Letter to ----, undated; 6-1/2x4; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
    A.L.S. with initials. 1p. In pencil. Could not find him in the Louvre. On same sheet as letter from Grenolat to [J. E. Gray].
  - Letter to "Dear Willimott", undated; 5-3/4x4-1/2; Green, Joseph Henry, 1791-1863
    Wednesday. A.L.S. 1p. Asks him to let Mr. Gray have a publication.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 6-1/2x4; Grenolat
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Wants to see him. On same sheet is letter from J. E. G[ray] to ----.
  - Post-script to a letter, undated; 2-1/2x3; Grey, J.
    A.L.S. 1p. Names a friend who will transmit anything for him.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 7-1/4x4-1/4; Gulliver, George, 1804-1882
    Wednesday afternoon. A.L.S. 1p. Has just been to the Zoological society. Davy is at Princes St. Sir John Richardson was with him at the Royal society.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray], undated; 4x3-1/2; Hakluyt Society
    A.L.S.: W. D. Cooley. 1p. Announces date of meeting.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; Hall, John
    May 14
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Hardy, Thomas Duffus, Sir
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Heids?, Brinsley J.
    October 14
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Henfrey, Arthur, 1819-1859
    January 2
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Hewitson, William chapman
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Hickson, William Edward
    Friday
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; Hillier, Henry Bentinck Curry
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Holland, C.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Jerichau-Baumann, Elizabeth, 1819-1881
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning the sale of a picture.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Johnston, John Taylor, 1820-1893
    June 22
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Johnston, George, 1797-1855
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 6x4; Kaup
    A.L.S. 1p. Complies with Mrs. Gray's request.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Kippist, Richard
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; King, Phillip
    Saturday
  - Specimen of handwriting, undated; 1-1/2x2-1/2; Lamarck, Jean Baptiste Pierre Antoine de Monet, de, 1744-1829
    A.D. 1p.
  - Specimen of handwriting, undated; 3x3-3/4; Lamarck, Jean Baptiste Pierre Antoine de Monet, de, 1744-1829
    A.D. 1p., end.
  - Observations sur votre dernier envoi, undated; 10x7-3/4; Lamouroux, M. (Jean Vincent Félix), 1779-1825
    A.D. 2p., end. In French.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Lankester, Edwin, 1814-1874
  - Letter to Mr. & Mrs. Brown, undated; 7x4-1/2; Lawrence, Abbott, 1792-1855
    London, A.L. in 3rd. P. 3p., end. He and his wife are busy the date suggested.
    April 1
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; Leake, William Martin
    April 13
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Lefevre?, George
  - Letter to ----, undated; 4-1/4x3-1/2; LeGendre, Adrien Marie, 1752-1833
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. Asks him to forward the enclosed letter to M. de Humboldt.
  - Letter to John Edwar Gray?, undated; Lemann, Charles
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Liddell, John, Sir
    May 16
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Lloyd, Llewelyn
    May 9
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; Lyon, Charles
    Tuesday
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Macnought?, John
    November 13
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Login, John, Sir
    January 16
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; MacCulloch, J.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; MacCulloch, J.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Main, Robert
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; Mayard?
    May 30
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Medley?
    May 23
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; Miles, William Augustus. Seraing
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Mitchell, David? William?
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; Murchison, Rodney Impey, Sir
    July 9
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Neale, Edward Vansittart
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Newton, Charles Thomas, Sir
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Oldfield, Edmund
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Oliver, Daniel, 1830-1916
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Paget, J.
  - Letter to [Karl Sigismund von] Kunth, undated; 2-3/4x5-1/4; Palisot de Beauvois, Ambroise-Marie-François-Joseph, 1752-1820.
    A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. In French. Asks a favor.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Parris, E.T.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Parry, John
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Phillips, ?
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Poole, Reginald Stuart
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Pouchet, Félix Archiméde, 1800-1872.
    Saturday evening. A.L.S. 1p. In French. Thanks for favors.
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Powell, C.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Powell, Baden, 1796-1860
    April 30
  - Letter to Mr and Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Powell, Baden, 1796-1860
    May 24
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; Power, William
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Prichard, James C. Cowles, 1786-1848
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Rae, John
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Rees, George Owen
    January 14?
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Reeves, John
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Reid, William, Sir
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Rennie, John
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Richards, William Upton
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Richardson, John, Sir, 1787-1865
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Richardson, John, Sir, 1787-1865
  - Letter to ----, undated; 9x7-1/4; Riego, Maria Teresa
    A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French. Thanks for her sympathy.
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Russell, John Scott
    May 20
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Russell, John Scott
    March 31
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; Russell?, M.A.
    January 22
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Salisbury, William
    July 22
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Saunders, W. Wilson, (William Wilson), 1809-1879
    February 13
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Schomburgk, Robert H. (Robert Hermann), Sir, 1804-1865
    A.L.S. 3p. Concerning natural history objects.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Selkirk, Lord
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Sharpey, William, 1802-1880
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Simon, John, 1818-1897
    July 26
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Simon, John, 1818-1897
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Smith, Collingwood
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Smith, Archibald
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; Smith, Gerard Edward
    November 19
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, , undated; Smyth, Annarella Warington
    March 11
  - Letter to T. Bramah, undated; Smyth, W. H., (William Henry), 1788-1865
    June? 12
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; Sopwith, Thomas, 1803-1879
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Spittal, Robert
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Stokes, Captain
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Stokes, John Lort
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; Stranger, W.
    November 21
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; Strickland, H. E., (Hugh Edwin), 1811-1853
    November 10
  - Letter to Mr. & Mrs. Gray, , undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Svedborn, Sven
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Swainson, William, 1789-1855
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Taylor, Richard C., (Richard Cowling), 1789-1851
    October 1
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Taylor, Laura W.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Taylor, Tom
    February 4?
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Thompson, T.P.E.
  - Letter to [John] Edward Gray, undated; Alexander Thomson, 1798-1848
    Euston Square, n.d. A.L.S. 1p. Soliciting sales of plaster casts of bones found in Norwich which Thomson believes belong to the Mastodon giganteum. 1. Mastodon giganteum. I. [Gray, John Edward?], 1800-1875.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; Thompson, Theophilus
    January 21
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Thomson, Thomas, 1817-1878
    August 17
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Tomes, John, Sir
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Tooke, Jr., Thomas
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Valenciennes, Achille, 1794-1865
    Sunday. A.L.S. 2p. In French. Concerning his work on fishes.
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Vaun, William J. W.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Vogel?, John?
    April 6
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; Wollaston, Thomas Vernon, 1822-1878
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; White, J. Charles
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Williams?
  - Letter to ?, undated; Winch, Nathaniel John
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, undated; Yates, James
    May 29
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated
    February 5
  - Letter to Mrs Gray, undated
    August 1
  - Letter to Mrs Gray, undated
    June 13
  - Letter to Mrs Gray, undated
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated
    May 22
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated
    May 31?
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated
    Fragment
  - Letter to Mr. White, undated
  - Addresses to various persons, undated; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875 (Drawer Oversize)
    Scrapbook of addresses collected by John Edward Gray
  - Autographs collected by John Edward Gray, undated; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
    Scrapbook of autographs collected by John Edward Gray
  - Envelopes--front sides, undated